# Kathryn Stoddard

Portland, OR | (971) 645-8114 | Kathryn.Stoddard@gmail.com https://github.com/kathrynstoddard | https://www.linkedin.com/in/kathrynpdx http://kathrynstoddard.com

## **Professional Summary**

Junior developer with a passion to learn and become a master front-end developer. A dedicated team player who is always willing to help, learn and teach. Looking to find a great company to work on projects that put an emphasis on user experience.

- 5+ years of experience in testing websites for content and filtration errors
- 7+ years of experience in marketing and customer service
- 8+ years of experience in finance, client and vendor relations

#### **Technical Skills**

Programming Languages: JavaScript, PHP

Markup Languages: HTML5, CSS3

Frameworks & Libraries: Bootstrap, Sass, jQuery, Backbone.js, Node.js

**CMS:** WordPress

Methods: Version control, Heroku and remote deployment

**Design:** Photoshop, Wireframes, Sketch

Related Proficiencies: Git, GitHub, Responsive Design, Chrome Developer Tools, Usability,

Web Standards

### Education & Professional Development

Full-Stack JavaScript Web Development, Portland Code School, Portland, OR (January 2014 - April 2014)

**Web Design & Development**, Portland Community College, Portland, OR (Completed 28 credits toward certificate January 2012 - December 2013)

B.S., Marketing, Minor, Psychology, University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah (2007)

### **Related Projects**

Axiom Equine - WordPress Website for Equine Leadership Training Company <a href="http://www.axiomequine.com/">http://www.axiomequine.com/</a>

Aug. 2014-Present

- Worked with client to determine website goals and content
- Created overall look and feel of website
- Using requirements outlined by client and design concepts from initial need finding, designed user interface in Sketch
- Created customized WordPress theme using the Genesis framework, HTML5/CSS3, PHP and relevant WordPress plugins.

Breeze - Online Weather Forecast App for Kite Surfer & Boarders <a href="http://breezeap-">http://breezeap-</a>

p.herokuapp.com/

Portland Code School

April 2014

- Worked on team of 4 to plan, build and deploy application using Git version control and GitHub
- Designed and implemented front-end of application using HTML5/CSS3, Bootstrap, Backbone.js and Handlebars.js
- Organized application's file structure incorporating Thorax framework with Backbone.js and Handlebars.js
- Tested site to ensure application was responsive across multiple browsers and devices

### **Professional Experience**

Customer Success Representative, Advisor Launchpad, Portland, OR (June 2015 - Present) Delivering customer service to clients and ensuring client requests are properly defined and running on schedule. Works with clients to maintain existing websites and web content using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript across multiple platforms, in-house content management systems, while promoting usability best practices.

**Event Registration Finance Manager**, CRG Events, Portland, OR (Dec. 2009 - June 2015) Ensured the financial processes during event registration were completed. Worked with clients and web development team to manage financial reports, tools, and processes for registration websites.

*Media Coordinator*, *Spherion*, *Portland*, *OR* (June 2009 - Dec. 2009)

Provided ongoing support for media buyers by creating media recaps designed to inform the account teams and clients of buy performance.

Assistant Finance Coordinator, CampusPoint, Portland, OR (Jan. 2009 - June 2009) Monitored and provided ongoing support to the registration and event staff in day-to-day operations for issues related to event finances.

Marketing Assistant, Mountain Land Rehabilitation, Salt Lake City, UT (Nov. 2007 - Aug. 2008)

Assisted in the creation and execution of marketing strategies for the inpatient division which reflect the brand, vision, and the philosophy of the company.

Client Services Coordinator, FranklinCovey, Salt Lake City, UT (May 2007 - Nov. 2007) Coordinated the accurate, timely delivery of various aspects of company seminars by working with facilitators and clients.

### **Affiliations**

Girl Develop It, TA, Portland Chapter (Aug. 2014 - Dec. 2014)